Pranida Ratarasan

Concept artist/ Visual Development artist/ Illustrator

SUMMARY

I am a creative visual development artist with a passion for character design, illustration, environmental design, and production art. I am proficient in Photoshop, Illustrator, Procreate, Blender, Maya, and I have broad knowledge of anatomy and volumetric drawing. I also have experience in music video, advertising, game and mascot design with large entertainment studios, including Netflix, Cartoon Network, Nintendo Switch, etc.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

The Monk Studios

Visual Development Artist

Bangkok, Thailand September 2020 – Present

- Adapted visual designs to make them suitable for 2D animation and to math with their environments for Cartoon Network asia.
- Researched and gathered information to create appropriate designs related to Indian culture to pitch at Disney Television Animation.
- Set team goals to maintain a proper pace of work.
- Developed assets and concept art to accelerate workflow for Netflix Original Series.

Igloo Studio

Senior Visual Development Artist

Bangkok, Thailand October 2019 - August 2020

- Executed character designs with toon shading techniques in the 3D model and anime style for President Bakery Public Company Limited, which reached 2.1 million views on youtube.
- Generated art styles in 3 projects and 1 teaser video for child cartoons.
- Managed 5 workers and conducted 2D art concepts for 2 music videos that reached
 2.4 million views on Youtube
- Translated directors' ideas into drawing in order to bring characters to life.

Visual Development Artist

January 2017 – October 2019

- Designed character personality, movement, attributes, performance and various expressions for Bounty Brawl Game to make each character unique.
- Produced outstanding and memorable main characters for an internal project.

ACHIEVEMENT

- The winner of Character design challenge, Character Design Challenge Group, 2019
- Character Licensing Workshop, Bangkok Thailand, 2018
- Asia Digital Art Award Fukuoka The Winner from Character Design, Fukuoka Japan, 2017
- Degree shows, Bangkok Thailand, 2016
- The 20th Shortflims and Video Festival, Bangkok Thailand, 2016

Skills

Illustration

Concept Art

Visual Development design

Character Design

Environment design

Entertaintment design

Programs

Photoshop

Illustrator

Zbrush

Blender

procreate

Education

Bachelor Degree June 2016 (Top 1 Nationally in Art)

Visual communication design
Decorative art
Silpakorn University
Honors: Second Class Honors
(GPA: 3.96)

CONTACT

pranida.ratarasan@gmail.com

pranidaportfolio.com

in pranida-rat

A pranida-rat